<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<metadata>
	<idinfo>
		<citation>
			<citeinfo>
				<origin>Department of Commerce (DOC), National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), National Ocean Service (NOS), Office of Coast Survey (OCS)</origin>
				<pubdate>20071116</pubdate>
				<title Sync="TRUE">Pacific_EEZ_dissolve_dd</title>
				<edition>v. 1.0</edition>
				<geoform Sync="TRUE">vector digital data</geoform>
				<pubinfo>
					<pubplace>Silver Spring, Maryland</pubplace>
					<publish>NOAA's Ocean Service, Office of Coast Survey (OCS)</publish>
				</pubinfo>
				<othercit>This data file is the culmination of work dating back to 2004. The baseline was reviewed and approved by the U.S. Baseline Committee on a region-by-region basis over a series of meetings on 20050426, 20050628, and 20050830.  The overall EEZ reviews and approvals were conducted at a meeting on 20061005.</othercit>
				<onlink>http://nauticalcharts.noaa.gov/csdl/eez.htm</onlink>
				<ftname Sync="TRUE">Pacific_EEZ_dissolve_dd</ftname></citeinfo>
		</citation>
		<descript>
			<abstract>
NOAA's Office of Coast Survey (OCS) is responsible for generating the Three Nautical Mile Line, Territorial Sea, Contiguous Zone, and Exclusive Economic Zone (EEZ).  Traditionally, these maritime limits have been generated by hand from the low water line depicted on paper, U.S. nautical charts.  Upon final approval by the U.S. Baseline Committee, these legally-binding maritime limits are applied to the next edition of nautical charts produced by the Marine Chart Division of OCS.

Due to new cartographic production processes and the availability of digital products such as Electronic Navigational Charts (ENCs), the Office of Coast Survey (OCS) is generating more accurate, digital maritime limits.  Through the use of Geographic Information Systems (GIS) software such as CARIS' LOTS and ESRI's ArcGIS, the latest vector representations of these limits will be available to NOAA cartographers and the public.

To create digital limits, the charted low water line is digitized from the largest-scale raster nautical charts and used as input to CARIS' LOTS:  Limits and Boundaries software for the designation of a baseline.  Other parts of the EEZ include maritime boundary agreements and/or unilateral claims as noted in Federal Register Notice, Volume 60, No. 163, Wednesday August 23, 1995.  Once the limits are created, they are exported to a shapefile using CARIS' "Import SHP File" utility.

Digital limits of the Exclusive Economic Zone for the West Coast of the United States are contained within a zipped file.  Within the zipped file is a shapefile and a text file detailing the individual coordinates.
</abstract>
			<purpose>This dataset is to be used as the source for the depiction of maritime limits on NOAA's paper nautical chart and electronic navigational chart. The EEZ was constructed from baseline points that represent the most seaward, drying features at mean lower low water on NOAA's largest scale, latest edition, raster nautical charts of the area, from maritime boundary agreements, and from unilateral claims set forth in Federal Register Notice, Volume 60, No. 163, Wednesday August 23, 1995.  This vector EEZ does not represent the official depiction of this maritime limit.</purpose>
			<langdata Sync="TRUE">en</langdata></descript>
		<timeperd>
			<timeinfo>
				<sngdate>
					<caldate>20071116</caldate>
				</sngdate>
			</timeinfo>
			<current>publication date</current>
		</timeperd>
		<status>
			<progress>Complete</progress>
			<update>Continually</update>
		</status>
		<spdom>
			<bounding>
				<westbc Sync="TRUE">-129.163671</westbc>
				<eastbc Sync="TRUE">-117.124668</eastbc>
				<northbc Sync="TRUE">49.002083</northbc>
				<southbc Sync="TRUE">30.542094</southbc>
			</bounding>
			<lboundng><leftbc Sync="TRUE">-129.163671</leftbc><rightbc Sync="TRUE">-117.124668</rightbc><bottombc Sync="TRUE">30.542094</bottombc><topbc Sync="TRUE">49.002083</topbc></lboundng></spdom>
		<keywords>
			<theme>
				<themekt>None</themekt>
				<themekey>GIS</themekey>
				<themekey>200 nautical mile limit</themekey>
				<themekey>Baseline</themekey>
				<themekey>US Mexico Boundary</themekey>
				<themekey>Exclusive Economic Zone</themekey>
				<themekey>Maritime Boundary</themekey>
				<themekey>Law of the Sea</themekey>
			</theme>
			<theme>
				<themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Category</themekt>
				<themekey>Planning Cadastre</themekey>
				<themekey>Boundaries</themekey>
			</theme>
			<place>
				<placekt>None</placekt>
				<placekey>Pacific Ocean</placekey>
				<placekey>West Coast</placekey>
				<placekey>California</placekey>
				<placekey>Oregon</placekey>
				<placekey>Washington</placekey>
				<placekey>Strait of Juan de Fuca</placekey>
				<placekey>San Nicolas Island</placekey>
				<placekey>San Miguel Island</placekey>
				<placekey>Point Arguello</placekey>
				<placekey>Piedras Blancas</placekey>
				<placekey>Cape San Martin</placekey>
				<placekey>Point Sur</placekey>
				<placekey>Farallon Islands</placekey>
				<placekey>Point Arena</placekey>
				<placekey>Gorda Rock</placekey>
				<placekey>Blunts Reef</placekey>
				<placekey>Little Black Rock</placekey>
				<placekey>Fox Rock</placekey>
				<placekey>Cape Arago</placekey>
				<placekey>Captain Cook Point</placekey>
				<placekey>Cape Perpetua</placekey>
				<placekey>Seal Rocks</placekey>
				<placekey>Cape Foulweather</placekey>
				<placekey>Government Point</placekey>
				<placekey>Cape Lookout</placekey>
				<placekey>Tillamook Rock</placekey>
				<placekey>Cape Disappointment</placekey>
				<placekey>Peacock Spit</placekey>
				<placekey>Sealion Rock</placekey>
				<placekey>Sea Lion Rock</placekey>
			</place>
		</keywords>
		<accconst>NONE</accconst>
		<useconst>NOT FOR LEGAL USE</useconst>
		<ptcontac>
			<cntinfo>
				<cntorgp>
					<cntorg>National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), National Ocean Service (NOS), Office of Coast Survey (OCS)</cntorg>
				</cntorgp>
				<cntpos>Chief Geographer</cntpos>
				<cntaddr>
					<addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
					<address>1315 East-West Highway N/CS</address>
					<city>Silver Spring</city>
					<state>Maryland</state>
					<postal>20910</postal>
					<country>USA</country>
				</cntaddr>
				<cntvoice>(301) 713-2780, x127</cntvoice>
				<cntfax>301-713-4019</cntfax>
				<cntemail>Meredith.Westington@noaa.gov</cntemail>
				<hours>Monday - Friday, 0900 EST - 1700 EST</hours>
			</cntinfo>
		</ptcontac>
		<native Sync="TRUE">Microsoft Windows XP Version 5.1 (Build 2600) Service Pack 3; ESRI ArcCatalog 9.3.1.1850</native>
		<natvform Sync="TRUE">Shapefile</natvform></idinfo>
	<dataqual>
		<attracc>
			<attraccr>
The baseline for the Pacific Coast EEZ was broken into sub-regions as follows:

Southern California, Northern California, and Oregon and Washington.

Each of these regions had a separate mapping file at 0.001 meter X/Y resolution with the exception of Southern California, which was set to .0002.  After the baseline was approved, the regions were combined into a smaller-scale Pacific map with an X/Y resolution of 0.001 meters.  Using the previously approved baselines, the "Envelope of Arcs from Normal Points" tool was run in LOTS to generate the 200nm line.  The following large-scale charts were determined to have baseline points that contributed to the 200nm EEZ:

18755,18727_1, 18721, 18700, 18686, 18645_2, 18645_1, 18640, 18623, 18620_1, 18603_1, 18589_1, 18580, 18561_1, 18521_1, 18520_1, 18500, 18480_1

Two portions of the EEZ capped to the south and north were derived from maritime boundary agreements between the US and Mexico in 1970 and 1978 as well as the US/Canada unilateral claim described in the 1995 Federal Register Notice.  Coordinates from these sources were converted to NAD83 using NADCON.  The attributes established in the EEZ shapefile include date of approval by the US Baseline Committee.  No added tests were conducted.
</attraccr>
		</attracc>
		<logic>The data, which reflects the largest scale nautical charts or hydrographic surveys of the area, are believed to be logically consistent.</logic>
		<complete>The EEZ delimitation is complete for the Pacific Coast of the United States.  The limits may be updated at a later date if the charted depiction of the farthest seaward low-water mark changes.  This limit was created for internal purposes only to improve the accuracy of the charted maritime limits. This vector EEZ does not represent the official depiction of this maritime limit.  For the official depiction of the EEZ, please see NOAA's paper or raster nautical charts.</complete>
		<posacc>
			<horizpa>
				<horizpar>No specific test was performed on the dataset. The data is a reflection of the largest scale raster nautical charts of the area. In cases such as the use of asterisk rocks (rocks awash), hydrographic surveys were referenced to determine if the features were drying at mean lower low water.  The number of decimal places used in the output format does not imply an accuracy level higher than the source chart documents.</horizpar>
			</horizpa>
			<vertacc>
				<vertaccr>The maritime limits are projected from a designated baseline.  Points representing the baseline are referenced from the farthest seaward low-water mark as depicted on the largest scale, raster nautical charts or hydrographic surveys.  No specific test was used to determine the vertical accuracy of the points.</vertaccr>
			</vertacc>
		</posacc>
		<lineage>
			<srcinfo>
				<srccite>
					<citeinfo>
						<origin>National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), National Ocean Service (NOS), Office of Coast Survey (OCS)</origin>
						<pubdate>1999-2005</pubdate>
						<title>Maptech's BSB-format raster nautical charts:  18755,18727_1, 18721, 18700, 18686, 18645_2, 18645_1, 18640, 18623, 18620_1, 18603_1, 18589_1, 18580, 18561_1, 18521_1, 18520_1, 18500, 18480_1</title>
						<edition>latest edition</edition>
						<geoform>map</geoform>
						<pubinfo>
							<pubplace>Silver Spring, Maryland</pubplace>
							<publish>NOAA's Ocean Service, Office of Coast Survey (OCS)</publish>
						</pubinfo>
						<onlink>Nautical Charts:  http://nauticalcharts.noaa.gov/staff/charts.htm</onlink>
					</citeinfo>
				</srccite>
				<srcscale>20,000</srcscale>
				<typesrc>online, raster nautical chart</typesrc>
				<srctime>
					<timeinfo>
						<rngdates>
							<begdate>1999</begdate>
							<enddate>2005</enddate>
						</rngdates>
					</timeinfo>
					<srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
				</srctime>
				<srccitea>BSB</srccitea>
				<srccontr>The maritime limits are created from normal baseline points.  Points representing the baseline are referenced from the farthest seaward low-water mark as depicted on the largest scale, paper nautical charts.  NOAA's raster nautical charts were used as backdrops in the CARIS map. As these charts were brought into the CARIS environment, the CARIS map was reprojected on the fly to match the chart's projection.  The latest edition charts as referenced in the citation information section above contained baseline points that impacted the 200nm EEZ.  The dates of these latest editions were current as of 2005.</srccontr>
			</srcinfo>
			<srcinfo>
				<srccite>
					<citeinfo>
						<origin>National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), National Ocean Service (NOS), Office of Coast Survey (OCS)</origin>
						<pubdate>1999-2005</pubdate>
						<title>Extracted Vector Shoreline of nautical charts:  18755,18727_1, 18721, 18700, 18686, 18645_2, 18645_1, 18640, 18623, 18620_1, 18603_1, 18589_1, 18580, 18561_1, 18521_1, 18520_1, 18500, 18480_1</title>
						<edition>latest edition</edition>
						<geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
						<pubinfo>
							<pubplace>Silver Spring, Maryland</pubplace>
							<publish>NOAA's Ocean Service, Office of Coast Survey (OCS)</publish>
						</pubinfo>
						<onlink>http://nauticalcharts.noaa.gov/csdl/ctp/cm_vs.htm</onlink>
					</citeinfo>
				</srccite>
				<srcscale>20,000</srcscale>
				<typesrc>online, vector</typesrc>
				<srctime>
					<timeinfo>
						<rngdates>
							<begdate>1999</begdate>
							<enddate>2005</enddate>
						</rngdates>
					</timeinfo>
					<srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
				</srctime>
				<srccitea>VECSHORE</srccitea>
				<srccontr>CARIS LOTS has a tool called the "Envelope of Arcs from Normal Points," which requires a vector low water line input in order to create the limits and determine contributing baseline points.   NOAA's Extracted Vector Shoreline (EVS) was used when available to make the job of boundary delimitation more efficient.  The EVS' mean lower low water and mean high water lines were merged using Safe's Feature Manipulation Engine (FME) to a single low water line.  Modification of the EVS occurred in the CARIS environment to achieve a 1 to 1 relationship between the raster nautical chart and the extracted low water line.  In some cases, either not enough information was provided in the EVS or there was no EVS available for a particular chart.  In these cases, the low water line was delineated through heads-up digitizing in the CARIS environment.  The resulting vector low water line was used as input to the "Envelope of Arcs from Normal Points" tool.  This vector low water line corresponds to the latest edition raster nautical chart as referenced in the citation information section above.  The dates of these latest editions were current as of 2005.</srccontr>
			</srcinfo>
			<srcinfo>
				<srccite>
					<citeinfo>
						<origin>Government Printing Office (GPO)</origin>
						<pubdate>19950823</pubdate>
						<title>Federal Register Notice- "Exclusive Economic Zone and Maritime Boundaries: Notice of Limits"</title>
						<geoform>document</geoform>
						<pubinfo>
							<pubplace>Washington, D.C.</pubplace>
							<publish>GPO</publish>
						</pubinfo>
						<onlink>http://www.gpoaccess.gov/fr/search.html</onlink>
					</citeinfo>
				</srccite>
				<typesrc>online</typesrc>
				<srctime>
					<timeinfo>
						<sngdate>
							<caldate>19950823</caldate>
						</sngdate>
					</timeinfo>
					<srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
				</srctime>
				<srccitea>FEDREG</srccitea>
				<srccontr>Representing the outer limit of U.S. jurisdiction at the Strait of Juan de Fuca, coordinates 1 through 17 under the "U.S. Pacific Coast (Washington, Oregon, and California)" section of the 1995 Federal Register Notice were converted to NAD83 using NADCON and imported into Caris LOTS.</srccontr>
			</srcinfo>
			<srcinfo>
				<srccite>
					<citeinfo>
						<origin>United States Government</origin>
						<pubdate>19720418</pubdate>
						<title>Treaty to Resolve Pending Boundary Differences and Maintain the Rio Grande and Colorado River as the International Boundary, 23 November 1970 (entry into force: 18 April 1972; registration date: 17 July 1972)</title>
						<pubinfo>
							<pubplace>Washington, DC</pubplace>
							<publish>United States Government</publish>
						</pubinfo>
						<onlink>http://www.ibwc.state.gov/Files/1970Treaty.pdf</onlink>
					</citeinfo>
				</srccite>
				<typesrc>online</typesrc>
				<srctime>
					<timeinfo>
						<sngdate>
							<caldate>19720418</caldate>
						</sngdate>
					</timeinfo>
					<srccurr>entry into force</srccurr>
				</srctime>
				<srccitea>US_MEX_1970</srccitea>
				<srccontr>The first 4 easternmost coordinates were pulled from the 1970 maritime boundary agreement and converted to NAD83 using NADCON.  All points were connected in LOTS using a geodesic line.</srccontr>
			</srcinfo>
			<srcinfo>
				<srccite>
					<citeinfo>
						<origin>United States Government</origin>
						<pubdate>19971113</pubdate>
						<title>Treaty on Maritime Boundaries between the United States of America and the United Mexican States (Caribbean Sea and Pacific Ocean), 4 May 1978 (entry into force: 13 November 1997; registration date: 12 April 2001)</title>
						<pubinfo>
							<pubplace>Washington, DC</pubplace>
							<publish>United States Government</publish>
						</pubinfo>
						<onlink>http://www.un.org/Depts/los/LEGISLATIONANDTREATIES/PDFFILES/TREATIES/MEX-USA1978MB.PDF</onlink>
					</citeinfo>
				</srccite>
				<typesrc>online</typesrc>
				<srctime>
					<timeinfo>
						<sngdate>
							<caldate>19971113</caldate>
						</sngdate>
					</timeinfo>
					<srccurr>entry into force</srccurr>
				</srctime>
				<srccitea>US_MEX_1978</srccitea>
				<srccontr>Coordinates OP-1, OP-2, OP-3, and OP-4 of the 1978 maritime boundary agreement were used to extend the geodesic line created from the 1970 maritime boundary treaty in the Pacific Ocean.  All coordinates were converted to NAD83 using NADCON and connected in LOTS using a geodesic line.</srccontr>
			</srcinfo>
			<procstep>
				<procdesc>The latest edition, largest scale charts were used to create a continuous vector low water line from which baseline points would be chosen. In the LOTS environment, the "Envelope of Arcs from Normal Points" tool was applied to the cleaned low water line. As input to the "Envelope of Arcs from Normal Points" tool, OCS selected the limit distance in nautical miles (200 for the EEZ) and designated the attributes for the baseline points. This tool generated the contributing baseline points and the boundary limit using a wagon-wheel filtering process of rolling a circle with a diameter specified by the limit distance (200 nm) and choosing the seaward-most points along the low water line.</procdesc>
				<srcused>BSB</srcused>
				<srcused>VECSHORE</srcused>
				<procdate>2006</procdate>
				<srcprod>BASEBOUNDS</srcprod>
			</procstep>
			<procstep>
				<procdesc>Coordinates 1 through 17 under the "U.S. Pacific Coast (Washington, Oregon, and California)" section of the 1995 Federal Register Notice and coordinates from the 1970 and 1978 maritime boundary agreements between the U.S. and Mexico were transferred to a text editor (UltraEdit 13.10a) for reformatting.  The data were reformatted to a space-delimited text file for NADCON batch conversion from NAD27 to NAD83.  From http://www.ngs.noaa.gov/cgi-bin/nadcon.prl, the NAD27 data was converted to NAD83 using the Free Format 2 option.  The output generated was in a format corresponding to the input file format.  The NAD83 output was reformatted again in a text editor to a comma-delimited text file for Caris LOTS import.  The comma-delimited NAD83 coordinate values were imported into LOTS using the "ASCII Data Importer" utility.  The "Join Nearest Points" tool was then used and the resulting line was converted to a geodesic line using the "Line to Geodesic" tool.  The resulting EEZ limits were then clipped and joined with the 200nm lines at the US/Mexico boundary and outside the Strait of Juan de Fuca using the "Join Lines" tool. The line was exported to shapefile format from CARIS LOTS as NAD83 using the "Import to SHP" tool.  The limits were further attributed in ArcGIS 9.2.</procdesc>
				<srcused>BASEBOUNDS</srcused>
				<srcused>FEDREG</srcused>
				<srcused>US_MEX_1970</srcused>
				<srcused>US_MEX_1978</srcused>
				<procdate>2007</procdate>
				<srcprod>SUBJECTDATASET</srcprod>
			</procstep>
			<procstep>
				<procdesc>A supplemental comma-delimited text file of points along the 200nm line with a spacing interval of 0.5nm was created from CARIS LOTS using the "Output as a Text File" tool.  The points were attributed in Microsoft Excel.  All turning points are listed in NAD83 and reflect coordinates transformed from NAD27 to NAD83 of the 1970 and 1978 US/Mexico maritime boundary agreements and the US/Canada unilateral claim listed in the 1995 Federal Register Notice.  The Excel spreadsheet of attributed, turning points was exported to a comma-delimited text file.</procdesc>
				<srcused>SUBJECTDATASET</srcused>
				<procdate>2007</procdate>
				<srcprod>EEZ_POINTS</srcprod>
			</procstep>
			<procstep><procdesc Sync="TRUE">Metadata imported.</procdesc><srcused Sync="TRUE">C:\DOCUME~1\WHITMI~1\LOCALS~1\Temp\xml4B8.tmp</srcused><date Sync="TRUE">20081104</date><time Sync="TRUE">14030600</time></procstep><procstep><procdesc Sync="TRUE">Dataset copied.</procdesc><srcused Sync="TRUE">\\BFB212J036FRAM\D\gis\MonitoringProgram\Survey\SurveyGrid\SurveyGrid.gdb</srcused><procdate Sync="TRUE">20090226</procdate><proctime Sync="TRUE">14283800</proctime></procstep><procstep><procdesc Sync="TRUE">Dataset copied.</procdesc><srcused Sync="TRUE">D:\gis\temp\Pacific_EEZ_segmented_dd</srcused><procdate Sync="TRUE">20090226</procdate><proctime Sync="TRUE">14290800</proctime></procstep></lineage>
	</dataqual>
	<spdoinfo>
		<direct Sync="TRUE">Vector</direct>
		<ptvctinf>
			<sdtsterm Name="Pacific_EEZ_dissolve_dd">
				<sdtstype Sync="TRUE">String</sdtstype>
				<ptvctcnt Sync="TRUE">0</ptvctcnt>
			</sdtsterm>
			<esriterm Name="Pacific_EEZ_dissolve_dd"><efeatyp Sync="TRUE">Simple</efeatyp><efeageom Sync="TRUE">Polyline</efeageom><esritopo Sync="TRUE">FALSE</esritopo><efeacnt Sync="TRUE">0</efeacnt><spindex Sync="TRUE">FALSE</spindex><linrefer Sync="TRUE">FALSE</linrefer></esriterm></ptvctinf>
	</spdoinfo>
	<spref>
		<horizsys>
			<geodetic>
				<horizdn Sync="TRUE">North American Datum of 1983</horizdn>
				<ellips Sync="TRUE">Geodetic Reference System 80</ellips>
				<semiaxis Sync="TRUE">6378137.000000</semiaxis>
				<denflat Sync="TRUE">298.257222</denflat>
			</geodetic>
			<cordsysn><geogcsn Sync="TRUE">GCS_North_American_1983</geogcsn></cordsysn><geograph><geogunit Sync="TRUE">Decimal degrees</geogunit><latres Sync="TRUE">0.000000</latres><longres Sync="TRUE">0.000000</longres></geograph></horizsys>
		<vertdef><altsys><altenc Sync="TRUE">Explicit elevation coordinate included with horizontal coordinates</altenc><altres Sync="TRUE">0.000100</altres></altsys></vertdef></spref>
	<eainfo>
		<detailed Name="Pacific_EEZ_dissolve_dd">
			<enttyp>
				<enttypl Sync="TRUE">Pacific_EEZ_dissolve_dd</enttypl>
				<enttypd>Shapefile Attribute Table</enttypd>
				<enttypds>None</enttypds>
				<enttypt Sync="TRUE">Feature Class</enttypt><enttypc Sync="TRUE">0</enttypc></enttyp>
			<attr><attrlabl Sync="TRUE">FID</attrlabl><attalias Sync="TRUE">FID</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">OID</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">4</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale><attrdef Sync="TRUE">Internal feature number.</attrdef><attrdefs Sync="TRUE">ESRI</attrdefs><attrdomv><udom Sync="TRUE">Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom></attrdomv></attr><attr>
				<attrlabl>Shape</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Feature geometry.</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom>
				</attrdomv>
				<attalias Sync="TRUE">Shape</attalias><attrtype Sync="TRUE">Geometry</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">0</attwidth><atprecis Sync="TRUE">0</atprecis><attscale Sync="TRUE">0</attscale></attr>
			<attr>
				<attrlabl>SRCDATUM</attrlabl>
				<attrdef>Datum of the source documents from which the limits are projected.</attrdef>
				<attrdefs>Office of Coast Survey</attrdefs>
				<attrdomv>
					<udom>Text description of the datum for determining the limits.  For example "NAD83/WGS84".</udom>
				</attrdomv>
				<attrtype Sync="TRUE">String</attrtype><attwidth Sync="TRUE">5</attwidth><attalias Sync="TRUE">SRCDATUM</attalias></attr>
		</detailed>
	</eainfo>
	<distinfo>
		<distrib>
			<cntinfo>
				<cntorgp>
					<cntorg>National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), National Ocean Service (NOS), Office of Coast Survey (OCS)</cntorg>
				</cntorgp>
				<cntpos>Chief Geographer</cntpos>
				<cntaddr>
					<addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
					<address>1315 East-West Highway N/CS</address>
					<city>Silver Spring</city>
					<state>Maryland</state>
					<postal>20910</postal>
					<country>USA</country>
				</cntaddr>
				<cntvoice>(301) 713-2780, x127</cntvoice>
				<cntfax>(301) 713-4019</cntfax>
				<cntemail>Meredith.Westington@noaa.gov</cntemail>
				<hours>Monday - Friday, 0900 EST - 1700 EST</hours>
			</cntinfo>
		</distrib>
		<resdesc>Downloadable Data</resdesc>
		<distliab>Users must assume responsibility to determine the appropriate use of this data set. The digital maritime limits do not represent the official depiction of the maritime limits.  The official depiction still remains the depiction on NOAA's nautical charts.  Please contact the Chief Geographer for more detailed information if required.</distliab>
		<stdorder>
			<digform>
				<digtinfo>
					<formname>SHP (ESRI line shapefile)</formname>
					<formverd>20071022</formverd>
					<transize Sync="TRUE">0.000</transize><dssize Sync="TRUE">0.000</dssize></digtinfo>
				<digtopt>
					<onlinopt>
						<computer>
							<networka>
								<networkr>http://nauticalcharts.noaa.gov/csdl/eez.htm</networkr>
							</networka>
						</computer>
					</onlinopt>
				</digtopt>
			</digform>
			<fees>None</fees>
		</stdorder>
	</distinfo>
	<metainfo>
		<metd Sync="TRUE">20090227</metd>
		<metc>
			<cntinfo>
				<cntorgp>
					<cntorg>National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), National Ocean Service (NOS), Office of Coast Survey (OCS)</cntorg>
					<cntper>REQUIRED: The person responsible for the metadata information.</cntper></cntorgp>
				<cntpos>Chief Geographer</cntpos>
				<cntaddr>
					<addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
					<address>1315 East-West Highway N/CS</address>
					<city>Silver Spring</city>
					<state>Maryland</state>
					<postal>20910</postal>
					<country>USA</country>
				</cntaddr>
				<cntvoice>(301) 713-2780 x127</cntvoice>
				<cntfax>(301) 713-4019</cntfax>
				<cntemail>Meredith.Westington@noaa.gov</cntemail>
				<hours>Monday - Friday, 0900 EST - 1700 EST</hours>
			</cntinfo>
		</metc>
		<metstdn Sync="TRUE">FGDC Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
		<metstdv Sync="TRUE">FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
		<mettc Sync="TRUE">local time</mettc>
		<langmeta Sync="TRUE">en</langmeta><metextns><onlink Sync="TRUE">http://www.esri.com/metadata/esriprof80.html</onlink><metprof Sync="TRUE">ESRI Metadata Profile</metprof></metextns></metainfo>
	<Esri><CreaDate>20090226</CreaDate><CreaTime>14290800</CreaTime><SyncOnce>FALSE</SyncOnce><SyncDate>20090227</SyncDate><SyncTime>10094000</SyncTime><ModDate>20090227</ModDate><ModTime>10094000</ModTime><DataProperties><lineage><Process ToolSource="C:\Program Files\ArcGIS\ArcToolbox\Toolboxes\Conversion Tools.tbx\FeatureClassToFeatureClass" Date="20081120" Time="145521">FeatureClassToFeatureClass D:\gis\NOSdata\pacific_eez_segmented.shp D:\gis\MonitoringProgram\Survey\SurveyGrid\SurveyGrid.gdb\MMA Pacific_EEZ_segmented # "Feature 'Feature' true true false 12 Text 0 0 ,First,#,D:\gis\NOSdata\pacific_eez_segmented.shp,Feature,-1,-1;LIMIT 'LIMIT' true true false 50 Text 0 0 ,First,#,D:\gis\NOSdata\pacific_eez_segmented.shp,LIMIT,-1,-1;LOCATION 'LOCATION' true true false 50 Text 0 0 ,First,#,D:\gis\NOSdata\pacific_eez_segmented.shp,LOCATION,-1,-1;SRCDATUM 'SRCDATUM' true true false 5 Text 0 0 ,First,#,D:\gis\NOSdata\pacific_eez_segmented.shp,SRCDATUM,-1,-1;SRCDATE 'SRCDATE' true true false 8 Date 0 0 ,First,#,D:\gis\NOSdata\pacific_eez_segmented.shp,SRCDATE,-1,-1;SOURCE 'SOURCE' true true false 50 Text 0 0 ,First,#,D:\gis\NOSdata\pacific_eez_segmented.shp,SOURCE,-1,-1" # D:\gis\MonitoringProgram\Survey\SurveyGrid\SurveyGrid.gdb\MMA\Pacific_EEZ_segmented</Process><Process ToolSource="C:\Program Files\ArcGIS\ArcToolbox\Toolboxes\Data Management Tools.tbx\Project" Date="20090226" Time="142838">Project D:\gis\MonitoringProgram\Survey\SurveyGrid\SurveyGrid.gdb\MMA\Pacific_EEZ_segmented D:\gis\temp\Pacific_EEZ_segmented_dd.shp GEOGCS['GCS_North_American_1983',DATUM['D_North_American_1983',SPHEROID['GRS_1980',6378137.0,298.257222101]],PRIMEM['Greenwich',0.0],UNIT['Degree',0.0174532925199433]] # PROJCS['NAD_1983_Albers',GEOGCS['GCS_North_American_1983',DATUM['D_North_American_1983',SPHEROID['GRS_1980',6378137.0,298.257222101]],PRIMEM['Greenwich',0.0],UNIT['Degree',0.0174532925199433]],PROJECTION['Albers'],PARAMETER['False_Easting',0.0],PARAMETER['False_Northing',0.0],PARAMETER['Central_Meridian',-126.0],PARAMETER['Standard_Parallel_1',32.0],PARAMETER['Standard_Parallel_2',48.0],PARAMETER['Latitude_Of_Origin',40.0],UNIT['Meter',1.0]]</Process><Process ToolSource="C:\Program Files\ArcGIS\ArcToolbox\Toolboxes\Data Management Tools.tbx\Dissolve" Date="20090227" Time="100943">Dissolve M:\assessment\Hicks\Pacific_EEZ_segmented_dd.shp M:\assessment\Hicks\Pacific_EEZ_dissolve_dd.shp SRCDATUM # MULTI_PART DISSOLVE_LINES</Process></lineage></DataProperties><MetaID>{4204E763-D7FD-434C-B3BC-BB5D3A4D9D1C}</MetaID></Esri><dataIdInfo><envirDesc Sync="TRUE">Microsoft Windows XP Version 5.1 (Build 2600) Service Pack 3; ESRI ArcCatalog 9.3.1.1850</envirDesc><dataLang><languageCode Sync="TRUE" value="en"></languageCode></dataLang><idCitation><resTitle Sync="TRUE">Pacific_EEZ_dissolve_dd</resTitle><presForm><PresFormCd Sync="TRUE" value="005"></PresFormCd></presForm></idCitation><spatRpType><SpatRepTypCd Sync="TRUE" value="001"></SpatRepTypCd></spatRpType><dataExt><geoEle><GeoBndBox esriExtentType="native"><westBL Sync="TRUE">-129.163671</westBL><eastBL Sync="TRUE">-117.124668</eastBL><northBL Sync="TRUE">49.002083</northBL><southBL Sync="TRUE">30.542094</southBL><exTypeCode Sync="TRUE">1</exTypeCode></GeoBndBox></geoEle></dataExt><geoBox esriExtentType="decdegrees"><westBL Sync="TRUE">-129.163671</westBL><eastBL Sync="TRUE">-117.124668</eastBL><northBL Sync="TRUE">49.002083</northBL><southBL Sync="TRUE">30.542094</southBL><exTypeCode Sync="TRUE">1</exTypeCode></geoBox></dataIdInfo><mdLang><languageCode Sync="TRUE" value="en"></languageCode></mdLang><mdStanName Sync="TRUE">ISO 19115 Geographic Information - Metadata</mdStanName><mdStanVer Sync="TRUE">DIS_ESRI1.0</mdStanVer><mdChar><CharSetCd Sync="TRUE" value="004"></CharSetCd></mdChar><mdHrLv><ScopeCd Sync="TRUE" value="005"></ScopeCd></mdHrLv><mdHrLvName Sync="TRUE">dataset</mdHrLvName><distInfo><distributor><distorTran><onLineSrc><orDesc Sync="TRUE">002</orDesc><linkage Sync="TRUE">file://\\Mlkapp\fram\assessment\Hicks\Pacific_EEZ_dissolve_dd.shp</linkage><protocol Sync="TRUE">Local Area Network</protocol></onLineSrc><transSize Sync="TRUE">0.000</transSize></distorTran><distorFormat><formatName Sync="TRUE">Shapefile</formatName></distorFormat></distributor></distInfo><refSysInfo><RefSystem><refSysID><identCode Sync="TRUE">GCS_North_American_1983</identCode></refSysID></RefSystem></refSysInfo><spatRepInfo><VectSpatRep><topLvl><TopoLevCd Sync="TRUE" value="001"></TopoLevCd></topLvl><geometObjs Name="Pacific_EEZ_dissolve_dd"><geoObjTyp><GeoObjTypCd Sync="TRUE" value="001"></GeoObjTypCd></geoObjTyp><geoObjCnt Sync="TRUE">0</geoObjCnt></geometObjs></VectSpatRep></spatRepInfo><mdDateSt Sync="TRUE">20090227</mdDateSt></metadata>
